IA'
[ indistinct chatter ]
[ William ] What went we out into this wilderness to find ?
Leaving our country , kindred
our father 's houses ?
We travailed a vast ocean ...
For what ? For what ' ?
[ Governor ] We must ask thee to be silent .
[ William ] Was it not for the pure and faithful dispensation of the Gospels
- and ihe Kingdom of God ? - [ Deputy governor ] No more !
We are your judges , and not you ours .
[ William ] I cannot bejudged by false Christians ,
for I have done nothing save preach Christ through gospel .
[ Governor ] Must you continue to dishonor
the laws of ( he commonwealth and the church with your prideful conceit ?
[ William ] If my conscience sees it fit .
[ Governor ] Then shall you be banished from this plantations liberties !
[ William ] I would be glad on it .
[ Governor ] Then take your leave and trouble us no further .
[ William ] How sadly hath the Lord testified against you .
Katherine .
Thomasin .
Come .
[ Katherine ] I will confess Jehovah with all head
tn secret and in assembly of { he just ...
singing continues , distant
[ dogs barking ]
I here confess I 've lived in sin .
I 've been idle of my work , disobedient to my parents ,
neglectful of my prayer .
I have , in secret , played upon my Sabbath .
And broken every one of thy commandments in thought .
Followed the desires of mine own will , and not the Holy Spirit .
I know I deserve more shame and misery in this fife
and everlasting hellfire .
But I beg Thee ... for the sake of Thy Son ...
forgive me , show me mercy ,
show me Thy light .
[ baby crying ]
Thomasin .
Frhomasin ] Boo !
[ laughing ] There you are , there you are .
Boo !
[ giggling ]
Where is Sam ? Where is Sam ?
Where is that little man ' ?
_ Boo ! [ giggling ]
There you are , there you are .
[ giggling ]
Boo !
Sam .
Samuel !
[ baby fussing ]
[ sobbing ]
[ sobbing continues ]
[ moans ]
Thomasin .
[ crying ]
Sleep .
All will be well , sleep .
[ crying ]
[ rooster crows ]
[ praying indistinct ]
Caleb .
God give you good morrow .
All are still a-bed .
Save Mother .
Tis no ease to rise on a gray day .
The Devil holds fast your eyelids .
- I 'll wake em . - No , lei em be .
Thy Mothefs not slept a night since ...
We can search no more , Caleb . We cannot .
If not a wolf , then hunger would have taken him yet .
Let 's to the wood .
Been a 'layin traps for some while now ,
even before this new misery .
Within the wood ?
Will thou not help thy father ?
You and Mother have always forbade us to set foot there .
Caleb , our harvest cannot last the winter .
We must catch our food if we cannot grow it .
We will conquer this wilderness . It will not consume us .
[ children playing ]
[ whispering prayers ]
[ crying ]
[ William ] Aren 't thou then born a sinner ?
[ Caleb ] Aye , I was conceived in sin and born in iniquity .
[ William ] Then what is thy birth sin ?
Adam 's sin imputed to me and a corrupt nature dwelling within me .
[ William ] Well remembered , Caleb , very well .
And canst thou tell me what thy corrupt nature is ?
My corrupt nature is empty of grace ,
bent unto sin , only unto sin and that continually .
[ William ] Soft now .
We must lay it again .
Was , was Samuel born a sinner ?
Aye .
Am I then- -
We pray he hath entered God 's Kingdom .
What wickedness hath he done ?
Place faith in God , Caleb .
We 'll speak no more on thy brother .
Why ?
He hath disappeared , not one week passed .
Yet you and Mother utter not his name .
He 's gone , Caleb .
- Tell me ! - Tell thee what ?
- Is he in hell ? - Caleb !
Mother will not stop her prayer .
And if I died , if I died this day ...
- What is this ' ? - I ought evil in me heart .
- Me sins are not pardoned ! - Thou an youngly yet- -
And if God will not hear my prayers ? !
- Caleb ! - Tell me !
Look you , I love thee marvelous well ,
but ' ( is God alone , not man ,
what knows who is the son of Abraham and who is not ,
who is good and who is evil .
Fain would I tell thee Sam sleeps in Jesus ,
that thou wilt , that I will .
But I cannot tell thee that . None can .
Caleb ?
Where are these from ?
From Indian Tom and old Slater , when last they past through .
What did you trade ?
Thy Mother 's silver cup .
[ egg cracks ]
Speak none of this to Mother . None .
She 's overwrought already .
I 'll tell her of the cup when her grief has passed .
Let 's not speak on this again .
Aye .
[ whistling ]
Fowler !
Fool of an animal .
[ 1109 barks ]
Fowler , what 's this ?
[ dog barking ]
Praise be to God . Make haste , Caleb .
Fie upon 't !
- Fa ( her , it died . - The other end .
[ dog barking ]
{ gun shot ]
Father ?
Father !
[ Qfoans ]
Fowler .
Black Phillip , Black Phillip , a crown grows on his head
Black Phillip , Black Phillip to nanny queen is wed
Jump to the fence post ...
- Jonas ! Mercy ! Come hither ! - Black Phillip , Black Phillip
King of all ...
Jonas ! Mercy !
Black Phillip , Black Phillip , king of sky and land
Black Phillip , Black Phillip , king of sea and sand
We are ye servants , we are ye men
Black Phillip eats the lions from the lions ' den .
Black Phillip , Black Phillip , a crown grows on his head ...
[ dog barking ]
Get back ! You two , stop that !
Phillip , back !
[ kids screaming ]
[ Katherine ] Heavens bless us !
[ dog barking ]
Caleb , hold the gate .
Caleb !
[ growling ] Get in !
Oh .
[ laughing ]
I 'll have thee quiet .
Wither were you and Caleb this morn ?
How could you disappear ?
And thee , I told thee to keep watch of Jonas and Mercy .
I was , and I bade them help me and they paid me no mind .
- I was a-getting . " - What 's the matter with thee , Thomasin ?
What is the matter with thee ' ?
Take thy father 's rags to the brook and wash them .
- They would pay me no mind . - And brush out his woolens .
Help him !
Wee one , it gave me such a fright to find thee gone .
I will not be left here alone . Dost hear ?
A morning 's work is well behindhand .
Jonas , leave thy sister be .
- She likes it . - William .
What , can 't a father spend Godly time with his son ?
Jonas !
- Father said stop it . - Thomasin !
" Slop - Stop m
Each of ya , stop it .
Thomasin , take the twins inside .
[ both ] No !
Get inside , get inside , get inside .
As you like .
We went to find apples !
In the valley .
I thought I seen an apple tree in the valley .
Father brought the gun , for if we glanced that wolf- -
Why did you not tell me ?
Father wanted it a surprise , to cheer you , and . "
but there were none .
I thought I seen em .
[ sigh ]
I like you not outside the farm , even to the valley .
Dost hear me ?
Caleb , be a good lad and get some water for thy Mother .
Stray not from the brook .
Why are you dallying ?
What then ' ?
What ?
Caleb ? Caleb !
Stop it .
I meant no harm in it .
Whats the matter with thee ?
Come hither .
Whats the matter with thee , eh ' ?
Shh .
I 've seen no apples since we went from England .
I would thou hadst found them .
I so wish for one .
[ makes biting sound ]
[ laughing ]
[ rustling ]
Hear that ?
Aye .
Who 's there ?
[ Mercy ] I be the Witch of the Wood !
Mercy , come out .
I be not Mercy ,
I be the Witch of the Wood and I have come to steal ye .
Hear me stick a-ﬂying through the trees :
C I ickety-clackity , clickety-clackity !
- Mercy ! - Clickety-clackity .
Why is 't when thou dost a wrong ,
I be a-washin Father 's clothes like a slave ,
- and thou an playing idle ? Because Mother hates you .
Spoilt child . I 'll tell Mother you 've left the farm alone ,
Black Phillip saith I can do what I like .
Devil take your Black Phillip .
It 's your fault I can 't leave the yard .
I could go to the brook before you let The Witch take Sam .
- Quiet , thee . - It were a wolf stole Sam .
Awitch . I 've seen her in her riding cloak , about the wood .
- Father showed me the tracks . - It was a witch .
Aye , it was a witch , Mercy , you speak aright .
- Thomasin ! - It was I.
Liar .
Twas I what stole him , I be the witch of the wood .
- Liar ! Liar ! - I am .
List not to her , Mercy .
I am that very witch .
When I sleep , my spirit slips away from my body
and dances naked with The Devil .
- That 's how I signed his book . - No .
He bade me bring him an unbaptized babe ,
so I stole Sam and I gave him to me master .
And I 'll make any man or thing else vanish I like .
- No . - Aye .
And I 'll vanish thee , too , if thou displeaseth me .
- Be quiet ! - Mercy , she 's but telling fantasies .
Perchance I boil and bake thee since we 're lack of food .
- No ! - Stop , Thomasin !
- L 'ts not true ! - It is , thou thing !
How I crave to sink my teeth into thy pink ﬂesh .
[ screaming ]
If ever thou tellst thy Mother of this ,
I 'll witch thee and thy Mother ! And Jonas too !
- Caleb ! - Stop thy tears and swear by silence .
- I swear it . - You 'll not tell Mother nor father .
- I swear . - Thomasin ! Let her alone .
Get away from her , Caleb , or she 'll witch thee !
Why tell Mercy those horrible fantasies ?
- Dost thou haie me now too ? - It was a wolf stole Sam .
Leave me be . Go tell Mother and father of my wickedness .
- Thomasin ... - I hate thy pity . I need it not .
And forgive us the sins we have this day committed against thee ,
free us from the shame and torment which are due unto us , Father .
We beseech thee , increase our faith in the promise of the Gospel ,
our fear of thy name and the hatred of all our sins ,
that we may be assured that the Holy Spirit dwells in us .
That we might be thy children in thy love and mercy ,
but as we hunger for this food of our bodies
so our souls hunger for the food of eternal life .
Finish soon our days of sin , and bring us to eternal peace
through the purifying blood of Thy Son ,
our Lord and only Savior Jesus Christ .
- Amen . - [ All ] Amen .
Thomasin , what 's thou done with the silver cup ?
ﬂhomasin ] ls 't not on the shelf ?
Nay .
In the six board , then .
T 'ain 't there neither .
It 's been disappeared for some while .
Didst lose it ?
I 've not touched it .
Where has it gone then ?
[ Thomasin ] I haven 't touched it .
[ Katherine ] I 've caught thee triﬂing with it before .
She says she haven 't touched it , Katherine .
How thou couldst lose my father 's silver wine cup in this hovel ,
- I cannot know . - I haven 't touched it .
Peace , child . It 's gone .
Did a wolf vanish that too ' ?
She haven 't touched it , Katherine .
What is amiss on this farm ? Hmm ?
It is not natural .
Caleb , will thou read out a chapter of the Word tonight ?
We must find some light in our darkness .
Tomorrow we will have a fast day but for our sins .
[ sheep bleating ]
Thomasin , dist not bed them down before supper ?
Baah , baah .
[ laughing ]
[ door creaking ]
[ sheep bleating ]
[ rustling ]
Oh , Holy and blessed Spirit , be with me and dwell in me heart .
You must sleep tonight , Kate .
This night and evermore , amen .
Thou dost rememberl love thee ?
[ sniffing ]
I do .
List me , Kate ,
I fear thou dost look too much upon this affliction .
We must turn our thoughts towards God , not to ourselves .
He hath never taken a child from us . Never a one , Kate .
Who might earn such grace ?
We have been grateful of God 's love .
[ Katherine ] He hath cursed this family .
No .
He hath taken us into a very low condition to humble us
and to show us more of His grace .
Was not Christ lead into the wilderness to be ill met by the Devil ?
We should ne 'er have left the plantation ,
Kate .
- We should never have left ! - That damned church .
- There 's naught hither ! - Well , what need we ? Silver chalices ?
How dare you chide me on a cup ?
Tis not for vanity that I am grieved of it .
[ sniffing ]
Katherine , I must tell thee- -
- We might have sold it . - What ?
What fool would trade for our corn ' ?
[ sniffing ]
List me , our daughter hath begat the sign of her womanhood .
Thomasin ? Caleb ?
Are you abed ?
Mercy ?
Jonas ' ?
She 's old enough . She must leave to serve another family .
[ William ] Twas not her fault . Kate , I must tell thee ...
[ Katherine ] Aye , it was thine for taking thy family hither .
[ William ] This is Godly land .
[ Katherine ] Godly ?
Our children are being fostered up like savages .
[ William ] Kate !
[ Katherine ] How oft I begged and begged thee to take Samuel for baptism ?
[ William ] They 'd not baptize outside the congregation .
[ Katherine ] Our Sam is in hell !
[ William ] Go to .
[ Katherine ] God save us , Caleb is well .
[ William ] We must keep him still . And Thomasin .
[ Katherine ] Our corn is trash !
[ William ] We cannot back to that church .
[ Katherine ] We will starve !
[ William ] Peace , peace . You 'll wake them , peace .
[ Katherine crying throughout ]
[ William ] I 'll lo the village with the horse and Thomasin tomorrow .
The Tildens or the Whythings ,
they can make use of her .
They 're good folk .
Stop , Kale .
We will find food , I know it .
Frhomasin ] Caleb ?
What are you doing ?
Go to sleep .
What is this ' ? Tell me , now .
- Running away then ? - No .
- Lie not to me . - I don 't .
Then what ?
Tell me !
If thou went back to sleep and kept silent of this ,
I promise thee ,
you 'll need not leave to serve the Tildens nor any family else .
I 'll be back by mid-day .
- Well , let me along with ya . - No .
- Let me along . - I cannot .
If you don 't let me along with ya ,
I 'll wake Mother and father this instant .
Well ?
Aye , but we did !
- Nay . - We did !
No .
We had glass windows in England .
We haven 't been hither so long you can forget that .
As you like , Thomasin ?
You 've gone mad .
Dost not remember Fowler laying on the floor in the sun ?
- You must ! - Nay ,
And where the sun would shine , would he warm himself .
Remember once he lay upon the table , and father saw him and he saith ,
" We will have him for meat !
Kale ! Kate ! We will roast this beast . "
You must remember that !
[ Caleb ] I rememberthat day , but no glass .
Well ... it was pretty .
[ dog barking ]
What is 't , boy ?
[ Caleb ] Burt , calm thee !
Fowler ! Nay , Fowler !
Stand here with Bun .
- Caleb , no . - I 'll straight back .
He 's gone mad !
[ Yelps ]
- Thomasin ! - Caleb !
- Thomasi n ! - Thomasi n !
- Caleb ! - Caleb !
- Thomasin ! - Caleb !
[ William ] Thomasin !
[ heavy breathing ]
Thomasin !
[ attempted whistling ]
Fowler !
[ heavy breathing ]
O God , my Lord , I now begin , o help me and I 'll leave my sin .
For I repentant now shall be , From evil I will turn to Thee .
None ever shall destroy my faith , nor do I mind what Satan saith .
O God , my Lord , I now begin , O , help me and I 'll leave my sin ,
For I repentant now shall be , from evil I will turn to Thee .
None ever shall destroy my faith ,
nor do I mind what Satan saith .
O God , my Lord , I now begin , O help me and I- -
[ dog barking ]
[ dog screaming ]
Caleb !
- Caleb ! - Father !
Thomasin .
Oh , my girl , my girl .
Where is thy brother ?
[ thunderstorm ]
[ heavy breathing ]
What 's the matter with thee , Thomasin ? Whats the matter with thee ?
I 'll set off at first light . I 'll not return until I 've found him .
T 'would be better to go to the village to raise up help , I cannot- -
[ William ] Tis a day 's ride and I have no horse .
There 's no time to be lost .
Likely you should have left this morn , ( hen .
You have no gun , William , nay , not even a dog .
- Be not a fool ! - I am a fool to go .
There is none will help this family .
Let me be !
The moon is bright , the rain bothers me not .
I 'll be back in a two-day , if any a man will return with me .
- Don 't go , Father ! - Enough !
Tell us why you went to the wood .
- I promised . - I care not !
Let me find favor in your eyes .
Oh , child , tell me and I will !
L , um ...
[ Katherine ] Speak !
L ...
I took thy father 's cup .
I sold it .
Forgive me , Kale . Forgive me , Thomasin .
What is this ?
Katherine , I must make confession .
I yestermorn took Caleb 10 lhe wood .
Twas for food , and the pelts for money , good money .
I knew you were false ! I knew it !
I meant it as a surprise , that is why I kept secret .
I will trap that wolf , Kate .
You stood by whilst our son lied to rne !
Twas for thy sake ! I love thee , Kate .
- You took him to the woods ! - I will find him !
You 've broken God 's covenant You 're a liar .
And you 've lost another child .
- I will go now . - You cannot escape the woods .
I will find him !
And kill thyself too ? Will Jonas be the man of the house ?
Will you damn all your family to death ? !
Katherine ! - Let go of me !
[ crying ]
Picking apples .
Mother , have the goats been bedded down yet ?
- Nay . - I 'll to it .
Let it wait til the morrow . They dare not escape with this rain .
[ Thomasin ] Nay , I 'll to it .
Please you , Mother .
Come hither , child .
Hurry back .
[ humming ]
[ rustling ]
[ gasps ]
Caleb ...
[ breathing heavily ]
Father !
Caleb , Caleb ...
Shh .
[ Katherine ] Oh , merciful Father ,
both the Lord and giver of life .
Thy sole , Jesus Christ , we beseech thee .
Look down from Heaven upon him
with those eyes of grace and compassion .
Pity thy wounded servant ...
[ rain falling ]
Baa , baa . Baa , baa , baa .
What ails Caleb , Black Phillip ' ? What ails him ?
Did Thomasin make ' im sick in the wood ?
What say you ?
Black Phillip says you are wicked .
Aye , he told me too .
Damn your Black Phillip .
He says you put the Devil in Caleb , that 's why he 's sick .
I 'd never hurt Caleb , nor Sam , nor thee .
- You beat me . - T 'was a jest .
- You said you 'd eat of me . - Mercy !
Mother and Father will find out .
- What ? - That you are a witch !
[ goats bleat ]
Thomasin !
Thomasin ?
[ Splash ]
[ Praying softly ]
Dost remember John Kempe 's son ?
That first winter , he was tormented of Indian magic .
'Us not the same .
- This is unnatural providence . - I know not that .
Look at thy son .
- Will . - What ?
- Think ! - Think what ?
- Think ! - I have no thoughts .
Does this not look like witchcraft ?
What witch ?
Who does this then ? Who ?
Thy thoughts are as a child .
What are you doing ?
We 'll back to ( he plantation in the morning .
Find a good family for Thomasin , take Caleb to the doctor 's .
He 'll tell if this be some natural ill or not .
Yet we cannot return as beggars .
I 'll scour the field . There must be some fruit yet untouched by this rot .
I beseech thee , Katherine , what canst thou do for him presently ?
How might we all bare it to the village with no horse ?
Well , the little corn and the goat should fetch a fair price .
We 'll ... We 'll back with Caleb and sell them ,
return with the horse for the twins and Thomasin .
- You cannot leave them here ! - Thomasin and thee ...
Oh , forget the crop , Will !
What ? !
What dost thou want , Katherine ?
Tell me and I will give it thee .
I want to be home .
Thou shall be home , by candle-time tomorrow .
In England .
[ Katherine subs and sighs ]
Oh , Will ...
I also have a confession to make .
I never meant to be a shrew to thee .
[ sobs ]
I have become as Job 's wife , I know it .
But since Sam , since ...
My heart has turned to stone .
[ sigh ]
I dreamed once , fwas when I was of Thomasin 's years ,
that I was with Christ upon Earth .
Oh , I was so very near Him .
And in many tears for the assurance of the pardon of me sins ,
And I was so ravaged with His love towards me ,
I thought it far exceeding the affection of the kindest husband .
And since Samuel disappeared
I have such a sad weakness of faith , I cannot shake it .
I cannot see Christ 's help as near .
I pray and I pray , but I cannot .
I fear I cannot ever feel that same measure of love again .
Thou shall have of it in Heaven .
I 'll be in field .
If you can spare a while , do .
We 'll leave at dawn .
I promise thee that .
Jonas , Mercy , come hither !
Speak not a word !
New " Biack Phillip is a merry , merry king
- He rules the land with mirth ... - Thomasin : I cannot abide your songs .
Please you , Mercy .
Black Phillip has a mighty , mighty sting
He ' ll knock thee to the Earth
Sing bah , bah , King Phillip , the black
- Sing bah , bah , bah , bah , bah - Thomasin : Peace , thou thing !
Mercy . Thornasin .
[ Mercy ] Sing bah , bah , King Phillip , the black
- He 'll knock thee on thy back ! - Thomasina : Enough !
[ scream ]
Come .
Get the broadaxe and cutoff her head .
Get the narrow axe and cutoff her head .
[ gasps ]
She 's upon me !
She kneels !
My bowels !
My stomach !
She pinches !
[ yelling indistinct ]
Sin ! Sin ! Sin !
Thomasin , take the children outside .
What dues ( his to thee ? What does this ?
His mouth has sealed up .
Oh , God , William !
William ! Get him up !
Hold him !
Children , away from this ! Thomasin , help !
[ William grunting ]
You 'll break his jaws .
[ Mercy ] Father !
What is ... ?
[ gruni ] [ choking ]
[ heavy breathing ]
[ Katherine ] William ... He is witched !
- ' Tis she ! - No !
- What horrible fancy is this ? - She told me she stole Sam !
Silence !
She gave him to the Devil in the wood !
- They lie ! - What say you ?
She turned Flora 's milk to blood !
She had bade us keep secret from you !
- It was but a jest to quiet her , I- - - She made bargain with Satan !
- She signed his book ! Silence !
Don 't let her near me ! She 'll put a curse on me !
- They conspire against me . - Thomasin is a witch !
Nay , I 'll not hear it .
I 'll have proof , or Heaven help thee .
On thy knees !
Look me in the eye , daughter .
- Dost thou love the word of God ? - Yes .
Love you The Bible ? Love you prayer ?
Yes . Yes !
We are children of sin all ,
yet I tell thee , I have raised up no witch in this house .
Let us pray , then we need fear nothing .
We shall never lie open to the wicked one .
Pray for thy brother .
- You must believe us ! - Evil wretches !
- Thomasi n ! - [ screams ]
Pray .
[ all ] Our Father , which art in Heaven , hallowed be thy name ...
Jonas , pray .
I ... I cannot remember my prayer . [ moans ]
- What ? - Nor I. I cannot .
What nonsense is this ?
Speak , children .
Our Father , which art in Heaven ...
- [ cries ] - ... hallowed be thy name
[ both crying ] Stop it ! Stop it !
Pray , you beasts . [ cries ]
- Get on thy knees and pray !
- Thomasi n ! - [ screams ]
I don 't hear this . This is not so .
[ screams ]
[ gasps ]
It 's her !
A cat .
A crow .
A raven . A three-legged dog . A wolf !
[ moans ] She desires of my blood .
She desires of my blood .
- Satan upon me ! - She desires of my blood !
[ all the children speaking over one another ]
She sends ' em upon me .
My Lord , my Jesus ! Save me !
- Think on Christ ! - She sends her devils !
I am thine enemy , wallowing in the blood of my sins !
The Lord is my shepherd , I shall not want
He maketh me to lie in green pastures ,
and leadeth me by the still water ...
[ Caleb ] I am thine enemy ...
[ prayers overlap ]
I am thine enemy ,
wallowing on the blood and filth of my sin !
- ... I will fear no evil - [ Caleb ] : For thou art with me .
[ panting ]
Caleb ... Caleb ...
Cast a light of countenance upon me .
Spread over me the lap of Thy love .
Wash me in the everflowing fountains of Thy blood .
Holy Thine I am , my sweet Lord Jesus .
My Lord , my love , kiss me with the kisses of Thy mouth .
How lovely art Thou .
Thy embrace !
My Lord ! naughs ]
My Lord ! MY love !
My sole salvation !
Take me ( o Thy lap !
[ laughs ]
[ gasps ]
[ moans of joy ]
Caleb ...
Caleb ?
Caleb .
W k [ sobs ] a e UP , please ! Wake up !
Wake up , wake up .
[ sobs ] Wake up .
[ wailing ]
He is dead !
[ wailing ] He is dead !
[ sobbing ]
Jonas , Mercy , get up .
Get up !
Get away from him ! Get thee gone !
[ sobbing ]
Thomasin !
Thomasin . Thomasin ...
My gm ...
[ wee pi F19 ]
This tree will be lovely come spring .
Do you remember when we came hither ?
Such a pretty tree .
Next year I 'll just own us a wheat field .
Stan it at this tree and end it thither .
We 'd have been a proper farm then .
Brought us a big fat milk cow , finished us the barn .
You must tell me , Thomasin .
Tomorrow I cannot keep secret of this .
The council will be called and thy life is- -
- Thy life- - - Will you not believe me ?
I saw The Serpent in my son . You stopped their prayer , Thom- -
- They lie ! - I saw it .
Caleb disappeared with thee .
- I love Caleb . - And who then found him ,
pale as death ,
naked as sin and witch 'd ?
Thomasin , listen to me .
The bargain that was made is of no effect .
- I made no bargain . - Thy soul belongeth to Christ .
- I made no bargain . - The Devil hath no interest in thee .
- I am no witch , father . - What did I but see in my house ?
- Will you not hear me ? - Prithee , confess .
Why have you turned against me ?
Christ can un-witch us if you will but speak truth to me .
As I love thee , speak truth .
- You ask me to speak truth ' ? - I beg thee .
You and Mother planned to rid the farm of me .
Aye , I heard you speak of it .
Is that truth ?
You took of Mother 's cup and let her rail at me .
You confessed not till it was too late .
- Is that truth ? - Peace thee .
- I will not . - I am thy father .
- You are a hypocrite ! - Hold thy tongue , daughter mine .
You took Caleb to the wood and let me take the blame of that too .
Is that truth ?
You let Mother be as thy master .
You cannot bring the crops to yield ! You cannot hunt !
- Is that truth enough ? - Enough .
Thou canst do nothing save cut wood !
Bitch !
[ screams ] And you will not hear me !
[ sobbing ]
Must I hear the Devil wag his tongue in thy mouth ?
[ sobs ]
Ask the twins then !
Go on , ask them !
They spend all day long babbling to that horned beast .
They know well his voice .
Go to .
The Adversary oft comes in the shape of a he-goat .
And whispers . Aye , whispers !
He is Lucifer . You know it .
- The twins know it too . - Slander thy brethren no more .
- It is they ! - From my sight !
Twas they and mat goat what bewitched this whole farm .
Lies .
Was " : a wolf stole Sam ?
I never saw no wolf .
Mercy told me herself by the stream ,
" I be the Witch of the Wood . "
Get up . Rise !
[ screams ]
[ Q ru nts ]
[ heavy breathing ]
[ thud ]
[ grunt ]
[ gasp ]
- What is this ' ? - [ William ] Speak .
I am no witch .
Gei her from me sight ! I 'll not have her in this house !
[ William ] She is no witch , Katherine .
What is the cause , daughter ? Tell thy Mother !
I cannot know for certain .
[ William ] Thou toldst me well thou knew .
[ Katherine ] I cannot look at her .
[ William ] Aye , but ye shall . Thomasin . Thomasin !
Jonas and Mercy .
They make covenant with the Devil in the shape of Black Phillip .
[ William ] Dost hear that , ye black minions ?
Dust hear that , you devils ?
Wake ! Wake from this !
Did ye makes some unholy bond with that goat ?
Speak , if this be pretense .
[ William laughs ]
Dissemblers ! Grave pretenders all .
Hear me this :
I will not play a fool to children 's games !
This is no sport , William .
Yet these lies from our babes ' mouths are but triﬂes to them .
- I do not lie . - Silence , creature !
Thy son is dead , damned !
- Caleb did but cry Jesus . - The Devil !
Thou know it not .
- The Devil will speak scripture too ! - Thou know it not .
- Tis not true ! - We are damned !
Wake !
Fetch the billhook , wife ,
and I will smile Jonas as Abraham would have done his seed .
No , stop it ! Stop it !
Fetch the billhook and I will dash his skull !
[ screams ]
- No ! - Do you see ?
- Stop it .. - - Do you see now ?
[ Katherine sobs ]
Please , father . No , it 's not safe . Not with them !
Keep me from this goat .
If that old billy be the Devil , I 'd have danced with him myself .
I 'll break thee out upon the dawn and we 'll set back to the plantation .
Think on thy sins .
[ crying ]
[ goat breathing ]
Are you witches ?
Does father think I am ?
Are you ?
No .
Does he really speak to thee ?
[ heavy breathing ]
[ Q ru nts ]
It is my fault .
[ sobs ]
I confess it .
Oh , my God .
My own fault .
I am infected with the filth of pride .
I know it .
I am .
Dispose of me how Thou will ' (
yet redeem my children .
They cannot tame their natural evils .
[ sobs ]
I lie before Thee a coward
and Thine enemy .
And I lick the dust of Thine earth .
[ sobs ]
I beg thee .
Save my children .
I beg Thee , my Christ ,
I have not damned my family .
[ rustling ]
[ gasps ]
Me lambs ... me angels !
[ whispering ] Mother , we have longed to see you so .
As I to thee .
I must wake thy father ! He will be so glad .
[ whispering ] No , let him sleep .
[ rustling ]
[ thud ]
[ heavy breathing ]
[ baby cooing ]
[ Caleb , whispering ] We would see you oft , Mother .
- Would ihal please you ? - Aye .
I have brought a book for you , Mother .
- Will you look at it with me ' ? - Aye .
Oh , one moment now . Samuel 's hungry .
[ Sam swing ]
Oh , come , come , little Sam .
Come , come .
[ slurping ]
Flora ? Flora ?
[ dripping ]
- [ laughs ]
[ choking ]
[ laughs ]
[ sighs ]
[ thud ] [ William groans ]
[ screams ]
[ moans ]
[ Q ru nts ]
Corruption .
Thou an my father .
[ Q ru nts ]
[ screams ]
- What hast thou done ? !
- Where are they ? - I know not what I saw .
- Where are they ? ! - I did nothing !
- She came from the sky ! She- - - Devil !
You have their blood upon thy hands !
[ crying ]
It is you !
- It is you ! - I am your daughter !
The Devil is in thee and have had thee .
You 're smeared of his sin . You reek of Evil !
- You 've made a covenant with death ! - Mother !
You bewitched thy brother , proud slut !
Did you not think I saw thy sluttish looks to him ,
bewitching his eye as any whore ' ?
- What say you to me ? - And thy father next !
No . [ Katherine sobs ]
You tookthem from me !
- They are gone . - No !
- You killed my children ! - No !
You killed thy father ! You witch !
I love you ! I love you !
[ screams ]
[ gasping ]
[ moans ]
[ muffled screams ]
[ crying ]
[ gasping ]
[ sobbing ]
[ birds chirping ]
[ chimes ]
Black Phillip , I conjure thee to speak to me .
Speak as thou doth speak to Jonas and Mercy .
Dost thou understand my English tongue ?
Answer me .
[ Black Phillip ] What dost thou want ?
What canst thou give ' ?
[ Black Phillip ] Wouldst thou like the taste of butter ?
A pretty dress ?
Wouldst thou like to live deliciously ?
Yes .
[ Black Phillip ] Wouldst thou like to see the world ?
What will you from me ?
[ Black Phillip ] Dost thou see a book before thee ?
[ chimes ]
Remove thy shift .
I cannot write my name .
[ Black Phillip ] I will guide thy hand .
[ whispering ]
[ chanting ]
IA'